晚上好，欢迎收看《卡尔佩珀分钟》。
Good evening, and welcome to The Culpeper Minute.
距离那本畅销自传《兜帽之下》揭露初代蒙面冒险家团队——
It's been nearly a decade. . .
——新生民兵的秘密，已过去近十年时光。
...since the best-selling autobiography Under the Hood...
1975年，《卡尔佩珀分钟》首度登陆广播频道时……
...revealed secrets of the original band of masked adventurers...
……我们曾专访《兜帽之下》的作者霍利斯·梅森……
...the new Minutemen.
……那位以"夜枭"之名闻名的前冒险家。
In 1975, when The Culpeper Minute was new to the airwaves...
当我的原始报道在1975年播出时，《基恩法案》尚未通过。
. . .we profiled the author of Under the Hood, Hollis Mason. . .
如今，这项颇具争议的法案已将一切变装冒险家与蒙面英雄定为非法。
...the former adventurer known as Nite Owl.
鉴于当前社会对蒙面正义议题的动荡氛围……
When my original report aired in 1 975, the Keene Act had not yet been passed.
……我们认为重温当年那期节目会颇具深意……
Now, this controversial bill outlawed all costumed adventurers and masked heroes.
……以此提醒人们这场变装英雄现象的……
Given our current climate of unrest around the subject of masked justice...
……起源之地。
...we thought it would be interesting to revisit that original episode...
今晚我们将与霍利斯·梅森畅谈他的自传《兜帽之下》。
. . .as a reminder of where the whole phenomena. . .
霍利斯·梅森的回忆录揭示了蒙面冒险家们……
...of costumed heroics began.
……不为人知的秘密。
Tonight we're talking with Hollis Mason about his autobiography, Under the Hood.
Hollis Mason's memoirs revealed some of the secrets...
...of the masked adventurers.
我在霍利斯最喜欢的纽约餐厅之一——恒河餐厅与他见面。
I met with Hollis at one of his favorite New York establishments, the Gunga Diner.
十二岁来到纽约……
Coming to New York at 1 2 years old...
……在很多方面，这对我来说，呃，都棒极了。
...it was, uh, fantastic for me in a lot of ways.
我父亲在第七大道旁的弗农汽车修理店找到了一份工作。
And my dad got a job at Vernon's Auto Repair off 7th Avenue.
-现在是梅森汽修，对吧？ -现在是梅森汽修。对，对。
-Now Mason's, right? -Now Mason's. Yeah, yeah.
同一个地方。
Same place.
卡尔佩珀：但你并没有追随父亲的脚步。你选择了另一条路。
CULPEPER: Yet you didn't follow in your father's footsteps. You chose another path.
梅森：嗯，是的，当我二十三岁时……
MASON: Well, yeah, when l was 23...
……我加入了纽约市警察局。
...l joined the New York City Police Department.
我认为这很大程度上与我祖父有关……
And l think that that had a lot to do with my grandfather...
……以及他灌输给我的价值观。
...and the values that he'd instilled in me.
因为在我人生的前十二年，我大部分时间都和祖父在一起。
Because for the first 1 2 years of my life, I spent a lot of time with my granddad.
他总是热衷于让我铭记……
He was always keen to impress upon me...
……乡下人在道德上比城里人更健康，这是他们的生活方式。
...that country folk were morally healthier than city folk, the way they lived.
当然，在某些方面你们会相互竞争，但你们也——
Of course you were competitive in certain ways, but you were also--
你们会互相帮助。
You helped each other.
这是一种深深印在我心中的道德价值观。
And it was kind of a moral value that stuck with me.
当我初到这座城市时……
And when I first got to the city...
...我目睹的一些事 真的让我感到恶心...
...there were things l saw that really filled me with disgust...
...我很难摆脱 而且 你知道 有些真的——
...that l found a hard time shaking, and, you know, some really--
有些我至今仍无法释怀。
Some of it l still can't.
我祖父教给我的...
What my grandfather gave me...
...以及我在城市里所面对的——
...and what I was confronted with in the city--
当这两者之间的差距太大 我无法承受时...
When the distance between those things got too great and I couldn't deal with it...
...我就会逃往我真正的另一个世界 通俗小说的世界。
...then l would go to my real other world, the world of pulp-fiction novels.
它们描绘了一个绝对价值的世界...
They described a world of absolute values...
...在那里 善与真从不被质疑。
...where what was good and true was never in doubt.
而恶——
And evil was--
嗯 它总会得到应有的惩罚。
Well, it received its appropriate punishment.
那么 你就是这样度过一生的吗？
Is that how you've led your life, then?
-我一直努力这么做 嗯... -嗯。
-That's what I've tried to do. Um.... -Mm-hm.
是的。
Yeah.
霍利斯·梅森 理想主义的年轻警察...
Hollis Mason, idealizing young cop...
...试图理解祖父的乡村价值观...
...trying to make sense of granddad's country values...
...与他所生活的大都市的残酷现实。
...and the grit of the big city he finds himself living in.
很快 警队及其正义品牌对年轻的梅森来说已不够。
Soon enough, the police force and its brand ofjustice is not enough for young Mason.
长久以来痴迷于侦探通俗小说和漫画英雄主义...
Long a fan of pulp detective fiction and comic-book heroics...
...梅森做了别人只敢幻想的事。
...Mason did what others only fantasize about.
他为自己做了伪装……
He made himself a disguise...
……在夜晚以义警的身份出动……
...and set out in the nights as a vigilante...
……按照自己的方式伸张正义。
...doling out justice on his own terms.
是什么影响了梅森行为的转变？
What influenced this shift in Mason's behavior?
想想还挺有趣的。
It's funny when you think about it.
你知道，我听过所有的——
You know, I've heard all the--
所有的笑话、所有的谣言和所有的影射。
All the jokes and all the rumors and all the innuendos.
对我来说，真正重要的是……
What it really comes down to for me...
……是我打扮成猫头鹰打击犯罪……
...is that l dressed up like an owl and l fought crime...
……因为那很有趣。
...because it was fun.
也因为那是正确的事。
And because it was the right thing to do.
还因为我确实乐在其中。
And because l darn well enjoyed it.
[梅森轻笑]
[MASON CHUCKLES]
我想这一切对我来说真正开始成形是在1938年。
I suppose it really started to take shape for me in 1 938.
在我的巡逻区域，有很多孩子在读《动作漫画》的第一期。
And on my beat there were a lot of kids reading that first issue of Action Comics.
我被深深吸引，无法自拔。
I was so drawn, I couldn't help it.
我问其中一个孩子能否借来看看。
I asked one of the kids if l could borrow it and take a look at it.
而《超人》的第一期……
And that first issue of Superman...
-……哇，让我震撼不已。-嗯。
-...wow, knocked me out. -Mm-hm.
好吧，超人对你影响最大，对很多孩子也是如此。
Okay, Superman was your biggest influence, and it was to a lot of kids.
但你走得更远。
But you took it even further.
梅森：嗯，一切都在我有一天翻开报纸时改变了……
MASON: Well, it all changed when l opened the newspaper one day...
……我看到这些角色从他们四色的世界中逃离出来……
...and l saw that these characters had escaped from their four-color world...
……他们现在身处报纸头条那真实的黑白世界里。
...and they were now in the factual black-and-white world of the headlines.
一次企图袭击和抢劫的事件被一个身影阻止了……
An attempted assault and robbery was thwarted by a figure...
……据说他是从上方跳入小巷的……
...who supposedly dropped into the alleyway from above...
……脸上蒙着东西。
...with something over his face.
然后他解除了三名袭击者的武装……
And he then proceeded to disarm the three attackers...
……并狠狠地殴打了他们，导致三人全部住院。
...and beat them with such severity that all three were hospitalized.
报纸开始称他为“兜帽判官”。
The newspapers started calling him Hooded Justice.
而那就是第一位蒙面义警。
And that was the first masked vigilante.
当我听到那个故事时，我立刻下定决心……
And when I heard that story I made up my mind right then...
……我要成为第二个。
...l was gonna be the second.
我们现在需要为赞助商休息一下，但当我们回来时……
We have to take a break for our sponsors now, but when we come back...
……我们将继续讲述1975年关于蒙面冒险家的故事。
...more from our 1 975 story on masked adventurers.
感谢您继续收听。
Thank you for staying with us.
我们现在回到对《兜帽之下》的回顾……
We return now to our retrospective look at Under the Hood...
……以及这些男男女女对我们今天的意义。
...and what these men and women mean to us today.
卡尔佩珀：你为什么想到设计猫头鹰服装？
CULPEPER: Why did you come up with the owl costume?
梅森：它真的是自然而然形成的……
MASON: It really came together...
...因为局里和我共事的另一个警察。
...because of another cop that l was working with in my station house.
他总在问下班后要不要一起去喝一杯。
And he kept asking me to go out for a beer after work.
而我总在拒绝，因为，你知道，我晚上要训练...
And l kept saying no, because, you know, I wanted to train at night...
...为我另一份事业做准备。
...and get ready for my other career.
然后他就开始叫我"夜猫子"。
And then he started calling me "night owl."
-你知道，他是在挖苦我。-没错。
-You know, he was being sarcastic. -Right.
但我很喜欢。我想，"好吧，就叫夜猫子吧。"
And l loved it. I thought, "Well, that's it, Nite Owl."
-所以名字就是这么来的？-就是这么来的。
-So that's where the name came from? -That's where it came from.
有了名字后，我就开始构思服装。
So once l had the name, then I could start thinking about the costume.
该不该有披风？该不该戴面具？
Should it have a cape or no cape? Should you have a mask or no mask?
最终，我把它精简到了最基本的要素。
Eventually, l just boiled it down to the basics.
我需要一套能自由活动的服装。
I needed a costume where l was free to move.
我需要保护身体。我需要保护头部。
I needed to protect my body. I needed to protect my head.
我还需要隐藏身份。
And l needed to protect my identity.
所以我做了这件覆盖着皮革和锁子甲的上衣...
So l did this with a tunic that was covered in leather and mail...
...一种钢制网眼。
...a kind of steel mesh.
我还有个头罩——同样是皮革和钢网制成的。
And l had a hood with-- It was leather and steel mesh again.
然后是短裤。也覆盖着同样的锁子甲。
And then briefs. They were covered in the same mail.
所以我把头发遮起来，只需要一个小面具。
So l've got my hair covered and all l need is a little mask.
于是我用这个做了面具，就是这个面具。
So l did it with this. This is the mask.
我用酒精胶粘上了这个面具……
I attached this mask with a spirit gum...
……就是演员用来贴胡子和假须的那种。
...which is what actors use to put on mustaches and beards.
卡尔佩珀：结果发现，当时有好几个蒙面的冒险者。
CULPEPER: lt turned out, there were several masked adventurers at the time.
梅森：是的，在我首次亮相大约一个月后……
MASON: Yeah, about a month after I made my debut...
……头条新闻都是关于一个叫剪影的年轻女子。
...the headlines were all about a young woman called the Silhouette.
她揭露了一个经营儿童色情制品的奸诈出版商。
She had exposed a crooked publisher who was dealing in child pornography.
她还狠狠地揍了他一顿。他和他的两个摄影师，对吧？
And she gave him such a brutal beating. Him and his two cameramen, right?
嗯，那真是个轰动一时的故事。
Well, that was quite a story.
从那以后，事情发展得相当快。
From there it grew pretty quickly.
有传闻说有个穿得像飞蛾的男人……
There were stories of a man dressed like a moth...
……能在空中滑翔。
...who could glide through the air.
后来又有个故事，讲的是一个穿黄色连体工装服的男人……
And then there was a story of a man in a yellow boiler suit...
……他特别残忍和恶毒。
...who was particularly brutal and vicious.
在兜帽判官戏剧性登场后的12个月里……
In 12 months of Hooded Justice's dramatic entrance...
……至少出现了，哦，其他七个穿戏服的义务警员。
...there were at least, oh, seven other costumed vigilantes.
还有莎莉·朱庇特，她取了丝魂这个名字。
There was Sally Jupiter, who took the name of Silk Spectre.
有美钞比尔，有飞蛾人……
There was Dollar Bill, there was Mothman...
……有剪影侠，有笑匠。
...there was the Silhouette, there was Comedian.
当然，还有我。
And, of course, there was me.
梅森告诉我的事情，大多已写在他的书里。
Little that Mason told me was not already in his book.
于是我转向他世界里的其他人物，以了解更多。
So l turned to some of the other figures from his world to find out more.
她利用自己的性感来打击犯罪……
She used her sexuality to fight crime...
……又凭借打击犯罪的经历在银幕上谋求事业。
...and her crime fighting to pursue a career on the silver screen.
如今她的女儿延续着她的形象……
Now her daughter lives on in her image...
……而生活似乎已将莎莉·朱庇特抛在身后。
...and life seemingly has passed Sally Jupiter by.
1975年，我们在她家中进行了以下对话。
We joined her at her home for the following exchange back in 1 975.
卡尔佩珀：为何取名丝魂？
CULPEPER: Why the name Silk Spectre?
朱庇特：说来有趣。
JUPITER: You know, it's funny.
很多人猜测过这个名字的由来。
Many people have hypothesized about reasons why that might have come up.
而事实上，我只是想找个神秘的名字……
And in truth, I wanted to find something mysterious...
……听起来顺耳的那种，明白吗？
...something that had a good ring to it, you know?
我觉得她应该是那种能从你指缝中溜走的人物。
And l felt that she should be somebody who could slip out of your hands.
要知道，当时丝袜非常昂贵。
Silk stockings, you know, were very expensive at the time.
我想，这名字确实朗朗上口——我只能这么解释了。
And it just had a good ring to it, l guess, is all I can really say.
你成为蒙面冒险家的动机是什么？
What were your motivations in becoming a masked adventurer?
我看到了兜帽判官……
I saw Hooded Justice...
……我觉得做点不同寻常的事——
...and l think the idea of doing something that was out of the normal--
我从未觉得自己真正融入过。
I never felt like l really fit in.
而成为丝鬼确实让我感觉更像找到了归属。
And l think that becoming Silk Spectre really made me feel actually more at home.
如今，丝鬼在海报和漫画中的形象都相当大胆。
Now, Silk Spectre is presented in fairly racy imagery in posters and in comics.
你如何处理这些我称之为视觉贬低的图片？
How do you deal with these, what I call, visually degrading pictures?
哦，我对那种事从来没什么意见。
Oh, l never had a problem with that sort of thing.
我是说，你知道，他们总把我称作性感符号。
I mean, you know, they always referred to me as a sex symbol.
我得说，我宁愿成为那样的符号……
And l have to say, I'd rather be a symbol of that...
……也不愿成为他们那些其他符号的象征。
...than a symbol for other things they've got symbols of.
你明白我的意思吗？
You know what l mean?
吉米·范图奇，一个著名的黑帮分子，我相信你听说过他。
Jimmy Fantucci, a famous mobster, I'm sure you've heard of him.
他实际上向警方自首了，因为他无法对我开枪。
He actually turned himself into the cops because he couldn't shoot me.
你知道，正如我所说，我从不回避自己的外貌。
You know, as l said, l never shied away from the way that I looked.
而且，事实上，在这种情况下，我似乎可以利用它。
And, in fact, it seemed in this case, I could use it.
蒙面冒险家或随便你们怎么称呼他们本质上都是商业行为。
Masked adventurers or whatever what you wanna call them is all about commerce.
你们必须记住这个国家是建立在娱乐业之上的。
You have to remember that this country was founded on entertainment.
当我管理丝鬼萨莉时……
And when I managed Sally, the Silk Spectre...
……我们利用她作为蒙面英雄的身份达成了各种利润丰厚的交易。
...we used her status as a costumed hero to make lucrative deals of every kind.
电影合约、海报形象授权、漫画书，无所不包。
Movie deals, image licensing for pinups, comic books, everything.
这种商业策略几乎立刻就被各大企业采纳了。
It was a business strategy that corporations picked up on almost immediately.
美元比尔原本是堪萨斯州的大学体育明星……
Dollar Bill was originally a star college athlete from Kansas...
……被一家大型百货公司聘用……
...hired by a major department store...
……因为他们意识到拥有自己的超级英雄……
...when they realized that having their own superhero...
……是个颇具前景的宣传策略。
...was an interesting publicity prospect.
不过我还是认为萨莉和我开创了这个概念。
Still, l like to think that Sally and I pioneered the concept.
当你想在世界上留下印记时，你需要帮助。
When you're trying to make a mark in the world, you need help.
你需要一个能起到凝聚作用的人……
You need someone who can be sort of the cohesive factor...
……将这种意识传递给公众，而他确实做到了。
...in bringing the awareness to the public, and he definitely did that.
而且我认为，实际上这可能牺牲了许多人的计划。
And l think, in fact, probably at the expense of many people's agendas, really.
我不认为你能做出价值判断……
I don't think you can make value judgments...
……关于蒙面英雄对社会是好是坏。
...on whether or not costumed heroes are good or bad for society.
这就像问电视是好是坏一样。
That's like asking if television is good or bad.
答案是两者皆有。
The answer is that it's both.
真正的问题始于我们聚在一起之后……
It was only really when we got together...
……问题才真正开始。
...that the problems started.
是的，就是民兵组织。
The Minutemen, yeah.
多棒的主意啊。
What a great idea.
我真希望这功劳能归我，但凭良心说我不能。
I wish I can take credit for it, but I can't in good conscience.
事情是这样的，有一天我收到了大都会队长写给莎莉的信。
The way it happened was one day l got a letter for Sally from Captain Metropolis.
他说他想聚在一起讨论这个想法……
He said he wanted to get together to discuss the idea...
……组建一个蒙面冒险家团体。
...of forming a group of masked adventurers.
起初，我以为他是想用这个主意作为把她弄上床的手段。
At first, I thought he was using the idea as a means to get her into bed.
然后我做了一些调查……
Then l did a little research...
……我了解到我的担忧……
...and l learned that my concerns...
……是的，是没有根据的……
...were, yeah, unfounded...
……如果你明白我的意思的话。
...if you get my meaning.
劳伦斯创建了民兵组织。
Lawrence made the Minutemen.
如果不是因为他和他的宣传天赋——
If it wasn't for him and his knack for publicity--
我想，作为你这一行的人，你大概能理解……
I mean l think as someone in your profession, you could probably understand...
……如果我们做了这次采访却没人看到，那么，噗，一切就都不重要了。
...that if we did this interview and no one saw it, then, poof, it doesn't matter.
谢克奈德：我意识到如果没有偶尔的噱头……
SHEXNAYDER: I realized that without the occasional gimmick...
……来重振日渐衰落的公众兴趣……
...to revitalize flagging public interest...
……这些穿着奇装异服的英雄热潮……
...the fad of costumed heroes...
……最终会逐渐消退，即使是那些打扮得像莎莉的人也不例外。
...would eventually fade, even the ones dressed like Sally.
经过一番考虑，我建议他们在《公报》上刊登一则大幅广告……
After some consideration l suggested they take a large ad out in the Gazette...
……邀请更多神秘人物挺身而出。
...asking for more mystery men to come forward.
这就是"民兵"组织的由来。
And that's how the Minutemen came to be.
卡尔佩珀：那么，当你第一次见到"笑匠"时……
CULPEPER: Now, when you first met The Comedian...
……"夜枭"、"剪影"和其他人……
...Nite Owl, Silhouette and the others...
……你当时有什么想法？你感到害怕吗？
...what were your thoughts? Were you intimidated?
是否有一种如释重负的感觉？
Was there a sense of relief?
哦，我必须说，那是一个令人难以置信的振奋人心的时期。
Oh, it was an incredibly exhilarating time, I have to say.
我想我们都觉得自己是家庭的一部分……
I think we all felt like we were part of a family...
……我们找到了某种归属地……
...that we had found sort of a place...
……在那里我们可以感觉自己确实是有价值的。
...where we could feel like we actually were of value.
每个人都为"民兵"带来了不同的东西。
Everyone brought something different to the Minutemen.
但不知何故，当我们在一起时，有一种团结的感觉……
But somehow when we were together there was a bonding feeling...
……我们都相信我们所做的事情。
...that we all believed in what we were doing.
现在，我之所以说"如释重负"，是因为在那个年代，许多人……
Now, the reason I say "relief" is because many of the people back in those days...
...认为你们都是相当古怪、不正常的人...
...thought that you were all rather bizarre, abnormal individuals...
...穿着儿童服装到处跑。
...running around in children's costumes.
朱庇特：我们只是普通人。
JUPITER: We were just people.
而且每个人的政治立场确实完全不同。
And everyone did have absolutely different politics.
我们中有些人是为了名声。有些人是为了权力。
Some of us were in it for fame. Some for power.
有些人可能是为了躲避这个世界。
Some to possibly hide from the rest of the world.
但归根结底，我们的政治立场并没有太多妨碍...
But in the end of the day, our politics really didn't get in the way too much...
...我们想要在那里做的事情，这是好事。
...of what we wanted to be there to do, which was good.
我们在各自的社区做了太多好事，不能被一笔勾销。
We did too much good in our respective communities just to be written off.
我们都试图通过个人的努力...
We were all attempting through our personal efforts...
...让我们的国家成为一个更好、更安全的居住地。
...to make our country a better and a safer place to live.
显然，霍利斯·梅森是一个对自己的人生...
Clearly, Hollis Mason is a man who makes no apologies...
...或所做的决定毫不后悔的人。
...for the life he's lived or the decisions he's made.
但他个人的道德准则是否足以成为...
But is his own personal moral code enough justification...
...戴上面具、执行私刑正义的理由？
...for donning a mask and dispensing vigilante justice?
我出去四处询问，以更好地了解...
I went out and asked around to get a better sense...
...你们，人民，对蒙面英雄的看法。
...of how you, the people, felt about masked heroes.
男子1：我不知道。
MAN 1 : I don't know.
我这儿有很多顾客是警察。
I get a lot of customers that are cops.
他们常来我这儿买包烟...
Guys that come by and pay for a pack of smokes from me...
...然后告诉我这些蒙面义警...
...and they tell me that these masked adventurers...
...让他们的工作变得更难了。
...they're making the job more difficult.
男子2：我怎么看他们？
MAN 2: What do I think of them?
他们几乎毁了我的生意，我可以这么说。
They've just about destroyed my business, I can tell you that.
他们把我的顾客弄成残废。
They maim my customers.
他们喜欢折断手指。他们觉得这很有趣。是的。他们很危险。
They like to break fingers. They think it's funny. Yeah. They're dangerous.
但另一方面，如果我们没有...
But then on the other hand, what if we hadn't had...
...那个曼哈顿博士站在我们这边，会怎样呢？
...that Dr. Manhattan guy on our side, huh?
我是说，我知道以我们现在所知来看，这难以想象...
I mean, l know it's inconceivable to us, now knowing what we know...
...但谁能说没有他们...
...but who's to say that things wouldn't have gone the same in Vietnam...
...越南的情况就不会一样呢？
...without them?
输掉那场战争。
Losing that war.
那会毁掉我们的国家。
That would've destroyed our country.
更多关于蒙面义警及其引发的争议...
More on costumed adventurers and the controversy surrounding them...
...将在赞助商信息后继续播报。
...after this word from our sponsors.
播报员：精工宣布推出世界首款数字石英液晶计时码表。
ANNOUNCER: Seiko announces the world's first digital quartz, liquid crystal chronograph.
它能显示时间、日期...
lt gives the time, the date...
...并且按下一个按钮，就能变成秒表...
...and with a push of a button, turns into a stopwatch...
...记录着圈速和冠亚军成绩，精确到十分之一秒。
...that records lap times and one-two finishes in tenths of seconds.
按下按钮，储存在电子记忆中的时间便会再次显现。
The time of day, kept in electronic memory, reappears when you push the button again.
精工液晶计时码表。
The Seiko liquid crystal chronograph.
这只是精工卓越数字石英腕表中的一款。
Only one of Seiko's superb digital quartz watches.
欢迎回来，感谢您的收看。
Welcome back, and thank you for watching.
在当前环境下，蒙面冒险者——守望者们的现实意义...
In our current climate, the relevance of masked adventurers, the Watchmen...
...比以往任何时候都更受质疑。
...is more in question than ever before.
我们现在继续回顾一档节目...
We continue now with our look back at a show...
...其中我们讨论了《兜帽之下》...
...in which we discussed Under the Hood...
...一本关于初代蒙面英雄夜枭（原名霍利斯·梅森）的回忆录。
...a memoir of original masked hero The Nite Owl, née Hollis Mason.
这本书引出了许多我们至今仍在探讨的问题...
A book which precipitated many of the questions we have today...
...关于这些游离于既定法律之外的男男女女。
...about these men and women who act apart from our prescribed laws ofjustice.
当然，有许多身着戏服的英雄值得深入研究。
Certainly there are many costumed heroes who would make for fascinating study.
我曾与精神病学家威廉·朗交谈...
I spoke with psychiatrist William Long...
...以获取一些专业见解。
...to gain some professional insight.
您知道，这是个有趣的问题。
You know, it's an interesting question.
大多数时候，我在监狱里与罪犯打交道。
Mostly, in the prison, I work with criminals.
所以我的看法可能略有偏差。
So my perception is slightly skewed.
我认为肯定有蒙面英雄……
I think certainly there are masked heroes...
……和超人类，比如曼哈顿博士……
...and superhumans, like Dr. Manhattan...
……他们只想做好事。
...that just want to do good.
我认为还有一些人不过是罪犯……
I think there are others that are nothing more than criminals...
……他们以此为手段……
...who used this as a means...
……来为自己的暴力倾向辩护。
...to justify their violent tendencies.
真正构成实际威胁的蒙面英雄……
The only masked heroes that pose an actual threat...
……是那些相对少数的边缘反社会者……
...are the relatively few borderline sociopaths...
……他们真心相信自己是在行善。
...that actually believe that they are doing good.
在那面具之下……
Beneath that mask...
……他们就像你我一样……
...they're just like you and me...
……有希望和欲望，有恐惧……
...with hopes and desires, fears...
……有爱。
...love.
我希望有一天……
I hope that one day...
……我能为这些蒙面英雄中的一位做心理分析。
...l can psychoanalyze one of these masked heroes.
那会很有意思。
That would be something.
如今看来那似乎是一个逝去的时代。
It seems a bygone era to us now.
喧嚣的四十年代，令人陶醉的日子。
The heady days of the roaring '40s.
人们渴望分心，渴求戏剧性的刺激。
People were eager for distraction, hungry for a fix of drama.
还有什么比一群自封的超级英雄……
What better than a group of self-designed superheroes...
……上演一场夸张的街头犯罪打击戏剧更好的呢？
...to act out an exaggerated street theater of crime fighting.
在一个充斥着超级反派的世界里……
And in a world populated by supervillains...
……何乐而不为呢？
...why not?
有臭名昭著的神秘法师莫洛克……
There was the notorious Moloch the Mystic...
……利用魔术表演的杂耍新奇感来掩饰他单枪匹马的恐怖浪潮。
...using the sideshow novelty of the magic show to front his one-man wave of terror.
当然，后来出现了像大人物这样的现代超级反派……
Later, of course, came modern supervillains like Big Figure...
……这位身材矮小的犯罪大师如今正在市监狱服无期徒刑。
...the diminutive master criminal now serving a life sentence in the city jail.
你以为我是威胁。
You think I'm the menace.
我可不是那个戴面具的人。我没什么好隐瞒的。
I'm not the one wearing a mask. I got nothing to hide.
那是什么样的人？戴面具？
What kind of person is that? Wear a mask?
我是个受人尊敬的商人。
I'm a respectable businessman.
卡尔佩珀：找到神秘法师莫洛克可不容易。
CULPEPER: It wasn't easy finding Moloch the Mystic.
但话说回来，嗯，也没那么难。
But then again, well, it wasn't too difficult.
你看，莫洛克，就像我们战后历史上许多臭名昭著的人物一样……
You see, Moloch, like so many infamous figures of our postwar past...
……只是过上了平民生活。
...had simply gone into civilian life.
莫洛克：那时我还年轻。
MOLOCH: I was a younger man then.
我很叛逆。
I was rebellious.
就像你看到的这些帮派，结顶帮。
Like these gangs you see around, the Knot Tops.
当你生活在一个有超人类权威人物的世界里……
When you live in a world with superhuman authority figures...
……而你想反抗，你就必须进行更大规模的抗争。
...and you wanna rebel, you have to rebel on a larger scale.
你得把事情升级，明白吗。
You have to escalate things, you see.
所以……
So...
……如果你在一个有超级英雄的世界里长大，而你想反抗……
...if you grow up in a world with superheroes and you wanna rebel...
……你就必须成为超级反派。
...you have to become a supervillain.
所以，是的，我认为没有超级英雄的社会会更好……
So, yeah, l think society is better off without the superheroes...
……因为那也意味着不再需要任何超级反派。
...because that means there's no need for any supervillains either.
梅森：谢谢。谢谢。
MASON: Thank you. Thanks.
你知道，它并没有持续，哦，十年。
You know, it didn't last, oh, 1 0 years.
当五十年代到来时，人们对蒙面冒险家的整体看法……
When the '50s came, the whole perception of costumed adventurers...
……你知道，改变了，明白吗？
...you know, changed, you know?
那是一种潮流，是的。
It was a fad, yeah.
而潮流正在消退，我们也随之消逝。
And the fad was dying out and we were dying with it.
[轻笑]
[CHUCKLES]
莎莉……
Sally...
……嗯，她怀孕了，然后离开了。
...well, she got pregnant and she left.
我们剩下的人，被迫在……
The rest of us, we were forced to testify...
……众议院非美活动调查委员会前作证。
...before the House Un-American Activities Committee.
那是一场政治迫害。
It was a witch hunt.
我们都被迫向其中一位代表……
We were all forced to reveal our identities...
……透露了我们的真实身份。
...to one of its representatives.
我是来自民兵组织的首都队长。
I am Captain Metropolis from the Minutemen.
梅森：现在，幸运的是，由于首都队长……
MASON: Now, luckily, with Captain Metropolis...
……拥有如此出色的军事记录……
...having such an outstanding military record...
……再加上我自己在警察部门的服务……
...and with my own service in the police force...
……我们俩或多或少都立刻摆脱了嫌疑。
...we both were more or less cleared of suspicion right away.
飞蛾侠遇到了更多困难，主要是因为他那些左翼朋友……
Mothman met with more difficulty, mostly because of the left-wing friends...
那是他在学生时代培养起来的。
...that he'd cultivated during his student days.
如今他终于洗清了冤屈……
Now, he's eventually cleared...
但调查过程如此漫长且残酷……
...but the investigations, they were so lengthy and so ruthless...
以至于我认为他所承受的压力……
...that l think that the pressure he was under...
加剧了他的酗酒问题……
...it exacerbated his drinking problem...
并最终导致了他的精神崩溃。
...and it caused his eventual mental breakdown.
兜帽判官……
Hooded Justice...
拒绝作证……
...refused to testify...
理由是他不准备向任何人透露自己的真实身份。
...on the grounds that he was not prepared to reveal his true identity to anybody.
而当他们逼迫他时……
And when they pressed him...
他便消失了。
...he disappeared.
为此我十分敬重他。
And l really respect him for that.
正是因为他，我才成为了夜枭……
He was the reason I became the Nite Owl...
而时至今日，我仍不知面具后的他究竟是谁。
...and l don't know to this day who he was behind that mask.
这难道不令人感慨吗？
Isn't that something?
[轻笑]
[CHUCKLES]
我了解到你离开民兵组织是因为怀孕了。
I understand that you wanted to leave the Minutemen because you got pregnant.
是这个原因吗？是否还有其他理由……
Is that the reason? Was there any other reasons...
让你从民兵组织退役？
...that you retired from the Minutemen?
朱庇特：你知道，有时候只是到了该向前看的时候。
JUPITER: You know, sometimes it's just time to move on.
我想如果没有怀孕，我可能会待得更久一些。
I think I would've stayed longer, had l not gotten pregnant.
但事实是——你知道，生活总会给你一些小小的提示，告诉你何时该退出。
But it was-- You know, life gives you those little signs of when to take the door out.
而那次似乎就是那个时机。
And that seemed to be the one.
在他的传记中，霍利斯声称你曾遭到喜剧演员的性侵。
In his biography, Hollis alleged that you were sexually assaulted by The Comedian.
但你对此从未发表过任何言论。
Yet you've never said anything about this.
嗯。
Hmm.
那么，我为什么要打破一辈子的习惯呢，对吧？
Well, why should l break a lifetime's habit now, right?
[轻笑]
[CHUCKLES]
作为记者，我理解你的提问，但，是的，这件事——
I can't blame you for asking as a reporter, but, yes, it's--
无可奉告。
No comment.
莎莉·朱庇特和喜剧演员之间的事件……
How much did the incident between Sally Jupiter and The Comedian...
……对你决定摘下面具有多大影响？
...affect your decision to hang up the mask?
嗯，那确实有很大关系，是的。
Well, that had lot to do with it, yeah.
我想一旦你意识到你的某些队友……
I think once you realize that some of your teammates...
……和你追捕的罪犯一样堕落……
...are just as depraved...
……一样扭曲……
...and twisted as the criminals you're going after....
是的。
Yeah.
那是我退出的主要原因。
That had a lot to do with why I quit.
那个传闻并非事实。
There's no truth to that rumor.
如果真发生了那样的事……
If something like that had happened...
……难道你不认为我会建议莎莉提起刑事诉讼吗？
...don't you think I would have advised Sally to have pressed criminal charges?
她是我最好的客户。是我最大的收入来源。
She was my best client. My biggest earner.
我绝不会让那样的事逍遥法外。
I would never allow something like that to go unpunished.
这不过是哗众取宠罢了。
It's nothing more than sensationalism.
自我炒作而已。
Self-promotion.
霍利斯·梅森想多卖几本书。
Hollis Mason wants to sell more books.
卡尔佩珀：笑匠拒绝发表评论。
CULPEPER: The Comedian declined to comment.
把那玩意儿从我面前拿开，否则我就把雪茄按在你眼睛里。
Get that thing out of my face before l put my cigar out in your eye.
《面罩之下》是本精彩绝伦的书。
Under the Hood is a fantastic book.
要知道，他也是我的顾客之一。
You know, he's one of my customers, you know.
我经常能见到他。
I see him all the time.
关于超级英雄这事儿很有意思，要知道，那条界限非常微妙。
It's funny about this superhero thing, you know, it's a very fine line.
当你遇到像夜枭这样的人……
And when you got somebody like the Nite Owl...
他是典型的超级英雄，因为在外人看来这家伙……
...who is your quintessential superhero, because outside you get this guy...
穿着戏服整天打打杀杀轰轰烈烈……
...who dresses up and does all the kaboom-kabang stuff...
但内里他其实是个警察。
...but inside he's a cop.
所以他是个明辨是非的人。明白我的意思吗？
So he's a guy who knows what's true blue. You know what l mean?
他不搞那些花里胡哨的名堂。
He's not into these kind of artsy-fartsy things.
他是个了不起的人。
He's a great man.
所以……
So...
我也说不清。
...l don't know.
很难判断这些蒙面英雄到底是好是坏……
Hard to say whether these masked-hero types are a good or a bad thing...
要知道，归根结底是这样。
...you know, in the final analysis.
值得注意的是早在1975年……
It's interesting to note that back in 1 975...
人们对这类存在仍存在巨大分歧……
...people were still very much divided as to whether or not...
所谓的蒙面义警对社会究竟有益还是有害。
...the so-called costumed adventurers were a benefit or a detriment to society.
鉴于本次访谈播出后发生的事件……
Given the events after this interview aired...
……或许霍利斯·梅森的退休来得正是时候。
...perhaps Hollis Mason's retirement came at the perfect time.
广告之后我们将继续聆听霍利斯·梅森的讲述。
We'll hear more from Hollis Mason after this commercial break.
播音员：为何如此多人选择洁厕灵……
ANNOUNCER: Why do so many choose Sani-Flush...
……而非其他主流马桶清洁剂？
...instead of the other leading bathroom-bowl cleaner?
洁厕灵拥有超凡效力。
Sani-Flush has extra power.
清洁马桶内壁，彻底洗净弯道。
Cleans inside the bowl and cleans right round the bend.
延时镜头显示，洁厕灵凭借其超凡效力……
Time-lapse shows Sani-Flush, with its extra power...
……能清除锈渍与沉积物……
...cleans away rust stains and deposits...
……深入马桶内壁，彻底洗净弯道。
...inside the bowl and right round the bend.
洁厕灵，拥有灭杀数百万细菌的强大功效。
Sani-Flush, with the power to kill germs by the millions.
洁厕灵。清洁马桶内壁，彻底洗净弯道。
Sani-Flush. Cleans inside the bowl and cleans right round the bend.
选择洁厕灵，粉剂或液体均可。
Get Sani-Flush, powder or liquid.
现在继续我对霍利斯·梅森的访谈。
Continuing now with my interview of Hollis Mason.
我们正在讨论蒙面义警的话题。
We're talking about costumed adventurers.
他被称为世界第八大奇迹。
He's been called the Eighth Wonder of the World.
我们的国家瑰宝。我们最伟大的希望。
Our national treasure. Our greatest hope.
但曼哈顿博士也被视为自然界的异类。
But Dr. Manhattan is also viewed as a freak of nature.
他的力量如此强大，不仅令敌人恐惧，也让我们自己心生畏惧。
His power is so great as to illicit fear not only in our enemies but in ourselves.
在他成为今日这般散发蓝光的超能存在之前……
Before he was the radiating blue superbeing he is today...
……他曾是乔恩·奥斯特曼，物理学家，钟表匠之子。
...he was Jon Osterman, physicist, son of a watchmaker.
一个拥有友情、爱情和普通家庭观念的人。
A man with friendships, loves, common family values.
他的一位朋友，实际上也是同事……
One of his friends and, in fact, colleagues...
……至今仍与曼哈顿博士共事……
...who continues to work with Dr. Manhattan today...
……本身就是一位备受尊敬的物理学家……
...is an esteemed physicist in his own right...
……沃利·韦弗。
...Wally Weaver.
我们前往韦弗的实验室，进行了如下对话。
We went to Weaver's lab and had the following conversation.
嗯，我认为……
Well, l think...
……各类英雄都是好事。
...heroes of all kinds are a good thing.
我指的是我们武装部队中勇敢的男女军人。
And l'm talking about the brave men and women of our Armed Forces.
我指的是警察和消防员。
I'm talking about the policemen and the firefighters.
我指的是科学家和医生。还有，呃……
I'm talking about the scientists and the doctors. And, uh....
是的，我也会把蒙面英雄……
Yeah, l'd include masked heroes...
……归入那类对社会有益的人群中。
...in that group that's a benefit to society too.
但乔恩——
Jon is--
抱歉，曼哈顿博士……
I'm sorry. Dr. Manhattan...
……完全是另一回事。
...is something else entirely.
我正在写一本书，讲述他如何永远改变了地缘政治格局……
I'm writing a book about how he's changed the geopolitical landscape forever...
……从根本上重塑了……的概念。
...essentially making the very idea...
...使得战争过时了。
...of war obsolete.
梅森：你知道，第一反应是完全难以置信。
MASON: You know, the first thing was absolute disbelief.
当然，正如你所知，也有狂喜。
Well, of course, as you know, there was elation too.
我的意思是，就像圣诞老人活生生地、生机勃勃地存在。
I mean, it was like Santa Claus was alive and thriving.
但恐惧……
But the fear....
那是一种可怕的恐惧……
It was a terrible fear...
……以及一种直击你核心的不确定性。
...and an uncertainty that went right to your core.
我当然能理解一辆旧车的感觉……
I certainly understood how an old car feels...
……当它看到一辆新车，一个新车型驶出来时。
...when it sees a new car, a new model come rolling out.
[轻笑]
[CHUCKLES]
但这不止如此。
But it was more than that.
你知道，我想我可以用三个字来概括那种感觉，真的。那就是：
You know, I think I can boil the feeling down to three words, really. lt's:
我们被取代了。
We've been replaced.
我指的不只是那些戴面具的冒险家。
And l don't just mean the masked adventurers.
我指的是，人类。
I mean, humanity.
我们被取代了。
We've been replaced.
霍利斯总是有戏剧性的天赋。
Hollis always did have a flair for the dramatic.
毫无疑问，这对我们所有人来说都是一个绝对的震惊。
There is no doubt that it was an absolute shock to all of us.
像曼哈顿博士这样的存在能够存在的事实。
The fact that anything could exist like Dr. Manhattan.
我的意思是，这对我们来说是超出概念范畴的东西。
I mean, this was something out of the realm of concept for us.
但我们永远需要人性……
But we will always have a need for humanity...
……无论我们在技术上如何扩展和成长，这是——
...and as much as we expand and grow technologically, it's--
我们仍然需要人类的接触，你知道吗？
We still need human contact, you know?
人们总是误解我关于乔恩的言论。
People have always misinterpreted what I said about Jon.
我并非将他比作神明。
I wasn't comparing him to God. I wasn't saying he was a god.
也未曾宣称他是神。
I just--
我只是——
Just wish I wouldn't have ever said that.
只是希望自己从未说过那些话。
Bottom line is this: Jon is still Jon.
归根结底：乔恩依然是乔恩。
At his core...
在他的本质里……
...he's still a man.
……他仍是凡人。
Well, take what I said about supervillains being a direct response...
那么，将我关于超级反派是直接回应……
...to the appearance of superheroes...
……超级英雄出现的言论……
...and apply that to the current scenario.
……套用到当前局势中。
If you have a being that can destroy...
若存在一个能凭一念之间……
...with a single thought...
……摧毁一切的存在……
...then the terrifying thing is that there is...
那么可怕之处在于……
...or there soon will be, a counterpoint or an adversary to that being.
……很快就会出现与之抗衡的对立者或敌手。
The universe has a way of finding its own equilibrium, its own level.
宇宙自有其寻找平衡与稳定之道。
What worries me is that Dr. Manhattan's nemesis will be arriving soon.
令我担忧的是，曼哈顿博士的宿敌即将到来。
Of course, some of these masked adventurers...
当然，有些蒙面冒险家……
...never stopped practicing their unique craft.
……从未停止磨练他们独特的技艺。
Eventually time moved forward to a point where their presence was again welcomed...
时光流转至某一刻，他们的存在再次被接纳……
...and some would say sorely needed.
……甚至有人会说已迫在眉睫。
Big city streets festered with violence...
恐吓与犯罪猖獗。
...intimidation and rampant crime.
这正是新型蒙面英雄诞生的绝佳土壤。
A perfect environment for a new breed of masked hero to emerge.
当然，我指的是守望者。
Of course, I speak of the Watchmen.
如今，随着冷战升级和真正超级存在的介入…
Now, with the Cold War escalating and the presence of a truly super being...
…成为我们国防的前沿力量…
...at the forefront of our national defense...
…一种日益增长的恐惧与不安似乎正渗透进民众之中。
...a growing fear and restlessness seems to permeate the population.
只是这一次，恐惧的对象并非罪犯…
Only this time, the fear is not of the criminals...
…而是打击犯罪者本身。
...but of the crime fighters themselves.
基恩参议员无疑认为时机已到…
Senator Keene surely thinks that the time has come to put an end...
…该终结蒙面义警的行为了。
...to masked adventuring.
他提出的新法律将有效束缚这些蒙面英雄的羽翼…
His suggested new laws would effectively clip the wings of these costumed heroes...
…迫使他们摘下自己的面具…
...making them hang up their masks...
…阻止他们在我们美好的街道上行使私刑正义。
...and preventing them from practicing vigilante justice in our fair streets.
基恩参议员是个投机主义的…
Senator Keene is an opportunistic...
…空洞符号。
...cipher.
他根本不明白自己在说什么。
He has no idea what he's talking about.
真正的问题在于警察部门。
The real problem are the police departments.
如果他们能多借鉴一些这些蒙面英雄的特质…
If they would take a little bit more of what these masked heroes have...
…我们就不需要基恩参议员这样的人了…
...then we wouldn't need people like Senator Keene...
...首先是在参议院。
...in the Senate in the first place.
我对基恩参议员有何看法？
What do I think about Senator Keene?
听着，我每天都在这里工作。
Listen, l work down here every day.
每当我遇到麻烦，每当有人在这里痛斥我...
Whenever I'm in trouble, whenever somebody's down here beating me up...
...而我大声呼救时，我不在乎是谁来救我的命。
...and l yell for help, l don't care who comes to save my butt.
我不在乎是超级英雄，也不在乎是警察。
I don't care if it's a superhero. I don't care if it's a cop.
只要有人在我喊"救命"时出现就行。
As long as somebody comes when l'm yelling "help."
你明白吗？
You understand?
人们...
People have...
...需要...
...a need for...
...一位日常英雄。
...an everyday hero.
无论是否蒙面。
Masked or otherwise.
而且，呃...
And, uh...
...那些明辨是非的人...
...people who know right from wrong...
...永远都会是需要的。
...will always be in demand.
那么此刻我想稍微谈点个人话题。
So l want to get a little personal here for the moment.
你从未结婚。这是为什么？
You never married. Why is that?
-嗯... -谢谢。
-Um.... -Thank you.
我想，如果非要找一个我从未结婚的理由...
Well, l suppose if there's any one reason why l never got married...
...那是因为...
...it was because...
...嗯，莎莉·朱庇特已经名花有主了。
...well, Sally Jupiter was taken.
我认为...
I don't think...
...我对她有好感，这算不上什么大秘密。
...it's any great secret that I had a thing for her.
当时一半的男性都对她有好感。
Half the male population did.
等我终于鼓起勇气，想约她正式出去约会时...
By the time l'd rustled up the courage to ask her out on a proper date...
...她已经嫁给了她的经纪人。
...she was already married to her manager.
[轻笑]
[CHUCKLES]
说起来还挺有趣的。
It's kind of funny when you think of it.
我每天扮成猫头鹰出生入死……
I dress up as an owl and risk my life on a daily basis...
……但到了约女孩出来的时候……
...but when it came to asking a girl out...
……我却束手无策。
...it was more than l could manage.
可悲的是，我觉得我们的婚姻从一开始就注定了失败。
Sadly, I think our marriage was doomed from the start.
我在莎莉生活中的职业身份让我很难成为一个好丈夫。
My professional position in Sally's life made it very difficult to be a good husband.
作为她的经纪人，我的工作……
It was my job as her manager...
……不仅是接受男人被她吸引的事实……
...to not only accept the fact that men were attracted to her...
……还要利用这种吸引力……
...but to build on that attraction...
……从中牟利。
...to prey upon it.
霍利斯对你来说非常重要。
Hollis was very important to you.
他是你生命中非常重要的人，对吗？
He was a very important person in your life, correct?
毫无疑问。
Absolutely.
-你们现在还有联系吗？-有的，有的。
-You stay in contact with each other today? -We do. We do.
不过我得说，联系不如我希望的那么频繁。
Not as much as l would like, I must say.
你知道，人生轨迹总会走向不同的方向……
You know, your life takes you in different directions...
……但那确实是一段不可思议的、梦幻般的时光……
...but that was really a magical, magical time...
……我们相聚时总爱聊起那些旧日往事。
...and we do like to talk about the old times when we get together.
你知道吗，我觉得——
You know, I think--
我觉得我心里还藏着某种……
I think I still have some kind of...
……不成熟的念头……
...half-baked idea that...
……关于夜枭和，呃……
...Nite Owl and, uh...
丝鬼和夜枭总有一天会在一起的。
...Silk Spectre are gonna end up together one day.
嗯。
Hm.
当初我们采访霍利斯·梅森时...
When we originally spoke with Hollis Mason...
...他相信他作为夜枭开创的传承...
...he believed that the legacy he'd begun as the Nite Owl...
...以及蒙面英雄群体的其他成员...
...along with other members of the masked-hero community...
...将在未来岁月中延续下去。
...would live on for years to come.
他当时不可能知道自己错得多么离谱。
He could not have known how wrong he was.
本期节目带我们怀旧回顾了这个国家历史上一个多彩的时代...
This has been a nostalgic look back at a colorful time in this nation's past...
...那时我们曾向身着卡通服装的浮夸英雄...
...when we turned to flamboyant heroes with cartoonish outfits...
...寻求道德指引。
...for our moral outlook.
在我们如今生活的后基恩法案时代...
In the post-Keene Act world we now live in...
...蒙面英雄已如同霍利斯·梅森在车库里修理的那些...
...the masked heroes are as outdated and irrelevant...
...破旧报废车辆般过时且无关紧要。
...as the old beat-up wrecks that Hollis Mason works on in his garage.
希望这次对制服冒险者历史的回顾...
We hope that you have found this look back at the history of costumed adventurers...
...能带给各位启迪与新知。
...both enlightening and informative.
我是《卡尔佩珀一分钟》的拉里·卡尔佩珀。
I'm Larry Culpeper for The Culpeper Minute.
[英文字幕]
[ENGLISH SDH]